<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jekyll on Technical Writing Joys and Woes</title>
    <link>https://blog.dougcuff.name/tags/jekyll/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jekyll on Technical Writing Joys and Woes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <managingEditor>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 08:50:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.dougcuff.name/tags/jekyll/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why no blog updates for the past month</title>
      <link>https://blog.dougcuff.name/posts/2024-06-13-starting-over-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 08:50:00 -0400</pubDate><author>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.dougcuff.name/posts/2024-06-13-starting-over-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned in Why no blog updates in over a year, I ran into some problems with Jekyll, the framework I used to publish blog entries. I eventually fixed the problem. Then I tried to update Jekyll. Which caused different problems.&#xA;So I&amp;rsquo;m done with Jekyll. I&amp;rsquo;ve moved to Hugo. While that is the name of Martin Scorscese&amp;rsquo;s only film for children, it&amp;rsquo;s also the name of another framework for building websites.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why no blog updates for over a year</title>
      <link>https://blog.dougcuff.name/posts/2024-03-02-absence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 10:56:15 -0400</pubDate><author>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.dougcuff.name/posts/2024-03-02-absence/</guid>
      <description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t been posting. Why? Because I ran into a technical issue that prevented me from connecting to GitHub. (Don’t know what that means? Essentially, I could write but not publish automatically.) Weekend after weekend, I tried to solve it.&#xA;I read post after post that claimed to have the fix. None of them helped. I have decent beginner&amp;rsquo;s technical skills, but I could not find a fix.&#xA;Eventually, I accepted that I was going to have to uninstall (part of) a commercial piece of software.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feeling appreciated</title>
      <link>https://blog.dougcuff.name/posts/2022-09-27-unintended-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate><author>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.dougcuff.name/posts/2022-09-27-unintended-use/</guid>
      <description>While walking through my local park, I ran into a former co-worker from 20 years back. I had been creating documentation; he had been supporting customers. He mentioned to me, 20 years later, how helpful my documentation had been for him.&#xA;I do strive to write clearly for both users who need a quick refresher and those who are approaching the product for the first time, so I wasn’t completely taken aback by his praise.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
