<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Communication on Technical Writing Joys and Woes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/communication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Communication on Technical Writing Joys and Woes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <managingEditor>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 10:25:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/communication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Meeting another reader</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-05-20-read-be-grateful/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 10:25:00 -0400</pubDate><author>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-05-20-read-be-grateful/</guid>
      <description>Readers are becoming increasingly rare. I &amp;ldquo;met&amp;rdquo; one recently through a second-hand book.&#xA;Years ago now, I bought a 86-page speciality instructional book in the consignment section of a specialty shop. For less than half the price of a new copy.&#xA;I still haven&amp;rsquo;t read it but, today, I set down to make the book ready for me to read. Does that sound pompous? I just mean that I was erasing the pencil marks that the previous reader left in it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Questioning assumption</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-04-21-assumptions-uncovering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate><author>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-04-21-assumptions-uncovering/</guid>
      <description>Assumptions engage our human emotions.&#xA;Some assumptions are embarrassing. CBC Radio &amp;ldquo;Morningside&amp;rdquo; host (the late) Peter Gzowski, long in a job that paid more than a living wage, once made the assumption that retirement tax breaks were available to all&amp;hellip; when they require a minimum income. Some assumptions are infuriating. In the &amp;ldquo;Doonebury&amp;rdquo; comic strip, cartoonist Garry Trudeau once did a masterful job of deflating privlege rather than ranting about it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On dropping a stone down a well</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-02-14-children-will-listen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate><author>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-02-14-children-will-listen/</guid>
      <description>The most recent time I was considering and being considered for a new technical writing position, I got a surprise. One of the managers mentioned my recent posting on this blog, Technical writers are not helicopters.&#xA;That was the first indication I had had that anyone ever read any of this blog.&#xA;Even in the smartphone age, writing is still like dropping a stone in a well and waiting to hear the splash.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technical writers are not helicopters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-12-08-helicopters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 10:56:14 -0400</pubDate><author>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-12-08-helicopters/</guid>
      <description>The majority of developers and their managers have absolutely no idea what technical writers do. Most developers think of us as old-school secretaries (administrative assistants) who correct their typographical errors and handle their typing. If you are a developer who knows better, please educate your peers rather than sending me a note with the message “not all developers.”&#xA;Developers frequently work with time pressure. They have limited time to code and debug a feature.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giving thanks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-10-09-thanksgiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 10:56:14 -0400</pubDate><author>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-10-09-thanksgiving/</guid>
      <description>Over the years, I have been blessed by working with terrific people.&#xA;Testers. Managers. Developers. Software architects. Customer support people at various levels. Fellow technical writers. Executives. Subject matter experts.&#xA;Quite a lot of these people could write a lot better than they thought they could. When they wrote, they thought about the user.&#xA;Some of them couldn&amp;rsquo;t write well but they were great at talking about what they wanted to write&amp;hellip; if only I could get enough of their time to interview them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Naming for the future</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-08-22-naming-a-class-the-same-as-an-instance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate><author>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-08-22-naming-a-class-the-same-as-an-instance/</guid>
      <description>How we ended up here: There is never enough time.&#xA;Software evolves over time. When writing the software, a developer creates a simple object and calls it Provider. Later, there&amp;rsquo;s a need for another object quite similar to Provider, so the harried developer takes most (but not all) of the attributes of the object Provider and creates a class. Which the developer also calls Provider. There&amp;rsquo;s no time to think of another name, and even if there were all the time in the world, the developer might not see a need to apply a better name.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On not telling everything you know</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-08-15-tell-what-you-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate><author>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-08-15-tell-what-you-know/</guid>
      <description>Do we, as technical writers, tell the reader everything we know? Do we heck!&#xA;We most emphatically do not. And listing just the reasons why we do not would take a long time and a lot of words. That&amp;rsquo;s listing the reasons, not explaining any of them. But let&amp;rsquo;s talk about one of the reasons.&#xA;Readers are busy people. If they read the documentation at all, it&amp;rsquo;s usually because they were using the product to get something done, and hit a roadblock.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are technical writers &#39;slow&#39;?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-08-01-are-we-slow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate><author>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-08-01-are-we-slow/</guid>
      <description>I spend most of my time at work thinking about the product users. Those are the people who will be reading what I wrote. That means I spend a lot of time considering what each person might not know, and might not know they don&amp;rsquo;t know. Part of the job of a technical writer is helping people learn. Which puts me in a very different head space than a lot of the people I work with.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everyone knows THAT!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-07-11-share-the-deadline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 12:15:00 -0400</pubDate><author>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-07-11-share-the-deadline/</guid>
      <description>Development can be incredibly self-focussed. Development managers and developers share information with members of the development team, and can be positively stunned to learn that not everyone has access.&#xA;Nowhere is this more obvious than when development is complete.&#xA;There is a belief that the deadline is available to technical writers, and in my experience, it is not available more than 50% of the time. There is a stronger belief that the availability of a feature to product users is known to everyone once development is complete.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
