<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Feedback on Technical Writing Joys and Woes</title>
    <link>https://blog.dougcuff.name/tags/feedback/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Feedback on Technical Writing Joys and Woes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <managingEditor>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 07:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.dougcuff.name/tags/feedback/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On dropping a stone down a well</title>
      <link>https://blog.dougcuff.name/posts/2023-02-14-children-will-listen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate><author>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.dougcuff.name/posts/2023-02-14-children-will-listen/</guid>
      <description>The most recent time I was considering and being considered for a new technical writing position, I got a surprise. One of the managers mentioned my recent posting on this blog, Technical writers are not helicopters.&#xA;That was the first indication I had had that anyone ever read any of this blog.&#xA;Even in the smartphone age, writing is still like dropping a stone in a well and waiting to hear the splash.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giving thanks</title>
      <link>https://blog.dougcuff.name/posts/2022-10-09-thanksgiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 10:56:14 -0400</pubDate><author>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.dougcuff.name/posts/2022-10-09-thanksgiving/</guid>
      <description>Over the years, I have been blessed by working with terrific people.&#xA;Testers. Managers. Developers. Software architects. Customer support people at various levels. Fellow technical writers. Executives. Subject matter experts.&#xA;Quite a lot of these people could write a lot better than they thought they could. When they wrote, they thought about the user.&#xA;Some of them couldn&amp;rsquo;t write well but they were great at talking about what they wanted to write&amp;hellip; if only I could get enough of their time to interview them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feeling appreciated</title>
      <link>https://blog.dougcuff.name/posts/2022-09-27-unintended-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate><author>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.dougcuff.name/posts/2022-09-27-unintended-use/</guid>
      <description>While walking through my local park, I ran into a former co-worker from 20 years back. I had been creating documentation; he had been supporting customers. He mentioned to me, 20 years later, how helpful my documentation had been for him.&#xA;I do strive to write clearly for both users who need a quick refresher and those who are approaching the product for the first time, so I wasn’t completely taken aback by his praise.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
