<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Non-Writers on Technical Writing Joys and Woes</title>
    <link>https://blog.dougcuff.name/tags/non-writers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Non-Writers on Technical Writing Joys and Woes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <managingEditor>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 15:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.dougcuff.name/tags/non-writers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Questioning assumption</title>
      <link>https://blog.dougcuff.name/posts/2024-04-21-assumptions-uncovering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate><author>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.dougcuff.name/posts/2024-04-21-assumptions-uncovering/</guid>
      <description>Assumptions engage our human emotions.&#xA;Some assumptions are embarrassing. CBC Radio &amp;ldquo;Morningside&amp;rdquo; host (the late) Peter Gzowski, long in a job that paid more than a living wage, once made the assumption that retirement tax breaks were available to all&amp;hellip; when they require a minimum income. Some assumptions are infuriating. In the &amp;ldquo;Doonebury&amp;rdquo; comic strip, cartoonist Garry Trudeau once did a masterful job of deflating privlege rather than ranting about it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Release notes for smartphone apps</title>
      <link>https://blog.dougcuff.name/posts/2024-04-07-release-notes-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 10:25:00 -0400</pubDate><author>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.dougcuff.name/posts/2024-04-07-release-notes-apps/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that there was a time when people actually read release notes? Not all people read them, but some regular customers did.&#xA;Since I became an iPhone user, I&amp;rsquo;ve started noticing the release notes for updated versions of iPhone apps. The only major software publisher that consistly explains what&amp;rsquo;s new in a release is&amp;hellip; Apple itself.&#xA;Streamlined in-app notifications inform you when a person joins a collaborative document for the first time Preseve file format and full quality when adding HEIC photos taken on iPhone or iPad On iPad, press and hold the Command key on a connected keyboard to select noncontigous words, sentences, or paragraphs using a trackpad or mouse It&amp;rsquo;s not new that the release notes are an afterthought.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In praise of the accuracy of subject matter experts</title>
      <link>https://blog.dougcuff.name/posts/2022-07-19-in-praise-of-sme-accuracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate><author>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.dougcuff.name/posts/2022-07-19-in-praise-of-sme-accuracy/</guid>
      <description>During the course of a career lasting over 20 years, would you care to guess how many times I have been given data from a software developer that later turned out not to be correct?&#xA;A maximum of three.&#xA;Once, another developer informed me that something I had written wasn&amp;rsquo;t true. I provided the developer with a copy of the e-mail in which a different developer had said it was true.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five duties of a technical writer</title>
      <link>https://blog.dougcuff.name/posts/2022-07-19-why-not-write/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 09:15:00 -0400</pubDate><author>doug@dougcuff.name (Doug Cuff)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.dougcuff.name/posts/2022-07-19-why-not-write/</guid>
      <description>Writing requires that you try to reach your reader. Technical writing doubly so. And that&amp;rsquo;s the part that isn&amp;rsquo;t easy. There are obstacles, and you have to do the work of overcoming all of them all of the time.&#xA;Here are five of my rules for technical writers.&#xA;You have to understand your topic.&#xA;In a lot of life, in conversations and in writing, you can have a vague idea of how something works.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
